

Personnel



Jared Rickenbach
President/ Project Manager

Michelle Dieffenbach
Treasurer/Architect

Diane Rickenbach
Vice-President

John Rickenbach Founder

y Parents, John and Diane started our company in Astoria in 1965. Now, 50 years later, my parents, my sister Michelle and I continue to bring our ethics and core values in all the projects we perform. Over five decades there have been challenges and triumphs, and we have worked through the challenges and celebrated the triumphs together in order to learn and grow into the company we are today. Together we have developed the skills needed for historic restoration, preservation, design build, commercial and residential construction.

We have always sought after projects that have been one of a kind and exciting. An example that we are very proud of is the restoration of the historic Liberty Theater that began in the year 2000. Another group of projects that requested us to stretch and grow was the work we have done for Columbia Memorial Hospital in the health care sector.

Whether it be a flagship project like the historical Liberty or a challenging more modern project like CMH, our team has studied, developed and worked together to gather the tools, training, and leadership skills necessary to be successful and service the community.

Together we have developed the skills needed for historic restoration, preservation, design build, commercial and residential construction.

With great pleasure I thank all of the wonderful employees, excellent subcontractors and suppliers and my family on this important milestone for our company. Most of all we are grateful to our customers and to the community which have been so supportive of our business.





The Crew



Left to Right: Scot Thompson, Jared Moss, Daymon Gardner, Tony Kurns, John Jolley, Sophie Allen, Mario Amador & Greg Allen. Not shown: Debbie Doughty



Jared Rickenbach Corporate President, Project Manager

RESUME HIGHLIGHTS

Historical Restoration and Renovation Experience
Healthcare /Patient Care Facility Experience
New Construction Experience
Renovation/Occupied Space Experience
Project Planning, Scheduling & Logistics
Excellent Relationship with Local Sub-contractors
Exceptional Communicator and Team Player



EDUCATION & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Bachelor of Construction Engineering Management, 1999 Oregon State University
Minor in Business Administration, 1999 Oregon State University
Rotary International: Astoria Club Member, 2005-Present
City of Astoria Gateway District Design Review Committee, 2006-Present
Dr. Edward Harvey Historical Preservation Award Recipient, 2008
NCBIA Local Builders Association Vice-president & President Elect 2007-Present
Fire Safety Training in Hospitals, Nursing Homes, and Hospice Completed June 11, 2009



Michelle Dieffenbach Corporate Treasurer, Architect, Project Manager

RESUME HIGHLIGHTS

Healthcare /Patient Care Facility Design Experience
New Construction Design Experience
Renovation/Occupied Space Design Experience
Historical Restoration and Renovation Design Experience



EDUCATION & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Bachelor of Architecture, 1989 University of Oregon
Registered Architect Oregon #3998
Registered Architect California #C24092
Dr. Edward Harvey Historical Preservation Award Recipient, 2008
Historical Landmarks Commissioner, 2007 – present





Diane Rickenbach

Corporate Vice-President, Project Manager

RESUME HIGHLIGHTS

Historical Restoration and Renovation Experience
Healthcare /Patient Care Facility Experience
New Construction Experience
Renovation/Occupied Space Experience
Project Planning, Scheduling, Logistics, Budgeting, and Value
Engineering.

Excellent Relationship with Local Sub-contractors and Suppliers Exceptional Communicator and Team Player



EDUCATION & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Over 40 years experience as Project Manager, Office Manager and Full Charge Bookkeeper



Greg Allen Project Manager

RESUME HIGHLIGHTS

Project Planning, Scheduling, Logistics, Budgeting, and Value Engineering Aerospace Manufacturing Engineering Excellent Relationship with Local Sub-contractors and Suppliers Exceptional Communicator and Team Player

EDUCATION & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Bachelor of Manufacturing Engineering Technologies, 2007 Weber State University

Barnes Aerospace Process Engineering Internship: 2005-2007

Fernhill Holly Farms, Production Manger 2007-2016

Fernhill Community Water System Board Member/Chair 2015-present.





Debbie Doughty Office Manager

RESUME HIGHLIGHTS

Numerous Banking positions over 10 year span.

Extensive Customer Service Training

Computer Software and Hardware Experience

Construction Loan Documentation Experience

Full Charge Bookkeeping

Payroll, Quarterly and Annual Tax Experience

Licensed Tax Preparer

Extensive Human Resource Experience

Safety Program Coordinator

Exceptional Communicator and Team Player

Leadership Abilities.

EDUCATION & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

1982-83 Attended Ricks College in Rexburg Idaho

1985-1995 Clatsop Community College—Various work related courses

1985-1995 American Bankers Association—Various work related courses

1998 Licensed Tax Preparer State of Oregon

EXPERIENCE

1985—1995 **Bank of Astoria**, Seaside, Astoria, Cannon Beach, Warrenton Branches. Positions include: New Accounts, Teller, Contract Collections and Loan Secretary.

1997-1999 **Paragon Tax Service**, Astoria Oregon. Duties included Bookkeeping and Tax Preparer.

1999-2005 Marxen & Hall Warrenton, Oregon. Licensed Tax Preparer, Payroll, Bookkeeping & Notary Public.

2005-2011 **Seaside Temps LLC**. Seaside, Oregon. Placement Specialist, Payroll, Bookkeeping & Notary Public.

2011 – Current Rickenbach Construction Inc. Office Manager